<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Davor Badrov</title>
    <link>https://davorbadrov.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Davor Badrov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017 Davor Badrov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davorbadrov.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chess clock</title>
      <link>https://davorbadrov.xyz/projects/chess-clock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davorbadrov.xyz/projects/chess-clock/</guid>
      <description>This is a PWA I made with Preact (and preact-cli). It&amp;rsquo;s an open sourced chess clock. It has a 100/100 lighthouse score. The project is hosted with Firebase and can be seen here. You can check it&amp;rsquo;s source here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid global node modules</title>
      <link>https://davorbadrov.xyz/blog/avoid-global-node-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davorbadrov.xyz/blog/avoid-global-node-modules/</guid>
      <description>I suggest avoiding project related global dependencies and installing everything you need for a project as main or dev dependencies. Sometimes you just want to hack something up and you do a npm i -g [package-name] and start coding without thinking about the consequences. For example my team used a globally installed sequelize-cli which later cause problems due to different versions being installed accross the team. It can cause problems for your personal projects too, if you have one project using sequelize 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments with comments for npm scripts</title>
      <link>https://davorbadrov.xyz/blog/experiments-with-comments-for-npm-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 12:53:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davorbadrov.xyz/blog/experiments-with-comments-for-npm-scripts/</guid>
      <description>The amount of npm scripts inside package.json can grow immensely for larger projects, it can become hard to track what each script does, especially if there are multiple people working on the same project and adding the mentioned scripts. It would be of huge help if we could comment what each script does so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to check what it does and how it&amp;rsquo;s used, but due to package.json being a JSON file format, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support any comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://davorbadrov.xyz/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davorbadrov.xyz/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a full stack engineer currently stationed in Zagreb, Croatia. My main stack is based on JavaScript, these days it revolves around React and Node (coupled with Hapi.js mostly). I&amp;rsquo;m part of a team working at Kanban (knb.io) where we are developing cool things for both startups and enterprises.
I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for freelancing opportunities and fun projects to work on. If you think we could work together you can check my resume on LinkedIn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://davorbadrov.xyz/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davorbadrov.xyz/home/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a full stack engineer currently stationed in Zagreb, Croatia. My main stack is based on JavaScript, these days it revolves around React and Node (coupled with Hapi.js mostly). I&amp;rsquo;m part of a team working at Kanban (knb.io) where we are developing cool things for both startups and enterprises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geocoding service</title>
      <link>https://davorbadrov.xyz/projects/geocoding-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davorbadrov.xyz/projects/geocoding-project/</guid>
      <description>A project I made in colaboration with Rade Koroman, my budy who is a designer. It&amp;rsquo;s a free and open source solution with an UI for getting coordinates for locations. You can check it here, and it&amp;rsquo;s source here.
It&amp;rsquo;s a frontend only project made in React and it uses OpenStreetMap&amp;rsquo;s Nominatim API free API for geolocation (getting coordinates out of locations). The app was bootstraped using create-react-app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://davorbadrov.xyz/projects/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 20:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davorbadrov.xyz/projects/projects/</guid>
      <description>These are projects I hacked together. Their source code can be found on https://github.com/davorbadrov.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>